

Dr Sunita Gandhi Educator

Contact



Phone

+91 94 150 150 31 +91 70 816 003 93



Email

sunitag@globaleducation.org sunitag@dignityeducation.org



Website

www.sunitagandhi.org

Other Links

www.dignityeducation.org www.globaleducation.org



Address

12 Statioan Road, Lucknow 226001, UP, India

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

2020

Shining World Caring Award, Ching Hai International Association, Taiwan'

2019

Best Woman Start-up Entrepreneur, IIM Lucknow

2017

Visionary of Uttar Pradesh Award**

2015

Honorary Doctorate, University of

2014

Educator of the Year, India Book of

1996

Most Outstanding Contribution to Development Award, World Bank***

*With a gift of USD 15,000 (donated the entire amount to DEVI Sansthan from source)

**Given by the two Deputy Chief Ministers of Uttar Pradesh, organized by DainikBhaskar.com, along with Visionaries of Uttar Pradesh Video https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DO2NiScsSMO

***Given for Project in Morocco on Participation of Women was showcased as one of top three from the World Bank at the UN Summit, Copenhagen in

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

2015	B.Ed. Lucknow University, India

1987 Ph.D. in Physics, Trinity College, Cambridge University, UK*

1983 B.Sc. (Hons.) in Physics, Imperial College, London University, UK

1980 A-Levels, Peterborough Technical College, UK

1975-1978 Middle & High School, St. Agnes' Loreto, Lucknow, India

1965-1974 Primary School, City Montessori School, Lucknow, India

*She received three merit scholarships to study Physics at Cambridge: Trinity College Scholarship, Overseas Student Award, and the Cambridge Commonwealth Trust Scholarship

CAREER SUMMARY

2014-Present Founder-CEO, Dignity Education Vision International (DEVI Sansthan), India*

2000-2007 President, Islensku menntasamtokin ses, Hafnarfjordur, <u>Iceland</u>

1998-Present President, Council for Global Education, USA

1988-1998 Economist, The World Bank, Washington, DC, USA**

1987-1988 Research Scientist, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratories, Berkeley University, USA

*Founded by Sunita Gandhi in 1992 on a visit to India; became its CEO in 2014; started the Global Dream Leave No One Behind Campaign for Literacy in 2014, which formed the basis of the ALfA, Accelerating Learning for All Pedagogy rolled out in 2022.

OTHER AFFILIATIONS

2016-Present Director, Global Education & Training Institute (GETI), India

2016-2019 Member, Confederation of Indian Industries, National Committee on

Education

2007-Present Chief Academic Advisor, City Montessori School, Lucknow, India

2007-Present Director, City International Schools, India

2006-Present Director, Global Classroom Pvt. Ltd., Lucknow, India*

2002 Founder Aslandsskoli and Tjarnaras (Iceland's first two charter schools)

2001 Founder, Islensku menntasamtokin SES (Education Society of Iceland)

1994 Founder, Global Concepts International School, Praha, The Czech Republic

1975 Founder, Little Flower School (for out-of-school-children)

^{**}Selected in the highly competitive Young Professionals Program (YPP) at the World Bank.

These schools have served as laboratory for experimental work in education. She has established or given franchise to 26 schools across India and is incubating an education based on the Ipsative principle of 'Compete with Yourself!' and ALfA: Accelerating Learning for All.

INTERNATIONAL VISITS & WORK

Dr. Gandhi has travelled to 50 countries and studied education systems of many of these:





Hungary

(U)

Iceland

Hong Kong

•



















Zimbabwe

Uzbekistan

PUBLICATIONS

Books:

Gandhi S., et.al. (2024) ALfA: A Groundbreaking Pedagogy to Transform Education. Bloomsbury, India.

Gandhi S., et.al. (2022), Disruptive Literacy: A Roadmap for Immediate Global Action. Bloomsbury, India.

Book Chapter:

Gandhi S. (2017) Compete With Yourself (CWY): Maximising Learning Gain in Schools. In: Hughes G. (eds) Ipsative Assessment and Personal Learning Gain. Palgrave Macmillan, London.

Research Papers:

The Inconvenient Truth of Indian Illiteracy Inequality: Intersectional Socio-Demographic <u>Disadvantage As A Climate Change Vulnerability Multiplier</u>, Sunita Gandhi, Kaaren Mathias, Linda Seefeldt, Thomas Delaney, Journal of New Economics, Centre for Development, Glasgow University, UK, November 2021

Intersectionality of Socio-demographic Disadvantage, The Inconvenient Truth of Illiteracy Inequality, Sunita Gandhi, Kaaren Mathias, Linda Seefeldt, Thomas Delaney, Economic & Political Weekly, August 2021

Reports*:

- Gandhi, S. Why Cant the Children Read (2019)
- Gandhi, S. Accelerating Adult Literacy (2019)

*Based on first-hand literacy survey of 1.5 million individuals 6-60 years of age in 396,000 households undertaken by Dr. Sunita Gandhi with the help of nearly 4000 government teachers of Lucknow

World Bank Reports & Papers

Morocco: Enhancing the Participation of Women in Development, Chapter 2, The Participation Sourcebook, World Bank, 1996, ISBN 0-82113-3558

World Bank Policy Paper: Energy Efficiency and Conservation in the Developing World, The World Bank's Role, 1993, ISBN 0-8213-2317-2, Robert J. Saunders & Sunita Gandhi

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCES & WORK TRAVELS

	2022	Chief Guest, 6th International Teachers Conference, Maldives
	2018	Keynote, <u>BETT ASIA, Malaysia</u>
	2017	Keynote, International Education Conference, Thailand
	2013	Keynote, <u>Annual Conference</u> , <u>Finnish National Board of Education</u> , <u>Finland</u>
	2009	Keynote, Australian Montessori Education Conference, Australia
	2000	Keynote, International Education Conference, Hawaii
•	2000	Keynote and Roundtable Host, <u>State-of-the-World-Forum</u> , Ireland
•	1999	Keynote and Roundtable Host, <u>State-of-the-World-Forum</u> , USA
•	1996	Keynote, <u>UN Summit, Copenhagen, Denmark</u>
•	1993	Keynote, <u>UN Womens Conference</u> , <u>Jordan</u>
•	1992	Keynote, A New Framework for Education, Finland

Speaker and participant in many conferences in several countries on issues of literacy, education, a new framework for education, and education policy, among others

2008-Present Convenor, Ed Leadership International Roundtable Conferences*

*In 2021, the 13th Ed Leadership Conference was on the theme as an Online Event: The Power of Change, Inspiring the Teacher Within. This was India's biggest education conference of India with 85 speakers from 37 countries, with over 19,000 educators from 50 countries participating *In 2022, the 14th Ed Leadership Conference, 4-6 August, 2022 will be on the theme Disruptive Education

*In 2022, First Synergy Summit for CSR Heads, July 9-11

*In 2023, First Policy Makers Conclave (online) and Roll-out of MOOTs: Massive Open Online Trainings

*In 2024, Second Synergy Summit for CSR Heads, January 11-12